## THOMAS HIGSON

Last updated November 2021

Thomas.Higson@gmail.com **4** +44 (0)7 540 848 925

<u>★ tomscv.azurewebsites.net</u> in TomHigson

### Summary

I am a technical product manager with 15 years' experience in software development, 6 of which in product roles. My background is in web development and cloud infrastructure.

As a certified agile practitioner and cloud leader, I enjoy helping each company I work with progress their agile and digital transformations.

My passion is to solve problems, balancing strategic and creative thinking, to make novel products that people love.

### **Qualifications**

- B.Sc. in Computer Science, 2007
- **PMI** Agile Certified Practitioner
- Google Cloud Digital Leader
- Mental health first aider









#### **Proficiencies**

#### **Methodologies Domains**

- Scrum
- Scrumban
- Kanban
- Lean
- SAFe

#### Languages

- TypeScipt
- HTML
- CSS
- Sass

- Software as a Service
- Customer/user satisfaction
- E-commerce
- Cloud platforms

#### **Tools**

- Jira
- Confluence

#### **Technology**

- AWS
- Azure
- Kubernetes
- REST
- OData
- Progressive Web Apps

#### **Awards**

- Contribution to the Business award, MBDA 2011 Awards
- award, Thales International Innovation Awards
- Project excellence award, the Ministry of Defence in 2008
- Highest MOD project feedback score, for all UK Thales Land and Joint Systems projects

### Career



### **Senior Product Manager Board Intelligence**

3 months Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

As the most senior product manager for Board Intelligence's primary Software as a Service offering, worth £20 Million in annual recurring revenue, I helped Board Intelligence keep ahead of rapidly emerging competition by infusing their unique domain knowledge into their products.

- I created a roadmap to balance the needs of few large and many small clients using value analysis.
- I simplified the product offerings to bring more value to smaller clients and reduce the manual testing effort by 20%.
- I built a strong relationship of trust with key stakeholders, making them comfortable trading requirements, even late into development.

I managed an agile team within Ocado's next generation grocery e-commerce solution.

Considering ¾ of the UK workforce eat the same lunch every working day, we worked to eliminate grocery tedium by making it effortless to find alternatives that align with your shopping interests, bringing greater satisfaction and better health.

- We ranked the relative needs and priorities for a bespoke recommendations engine that now outperforms the old engine across all metrics.
- We improved the discoverability of key user stories from 30% to 80%.
- I helped the robotics team prioritise work to maximise value using value stream analysis.

dyson

# **Technical Product Owner** (contractor) **Dyson**

6 months Sep 2019 – Mar 2020

I identified weak points and prioritised the most valuable opportunities for platform work across a group of 9 scrum teams.

Half of all the year's traffic is concentrated into the Christmas period; we ensured we could cope with this for the 2019 peak trading period by identifying and fixing bottlenecks in Dyson's international website's cloud architecture.

- We achieved zero downtime during the peak trading window for the first time in the site's history.
- We migrated the identity management system from a monolithic, unsupported, legacy system to a modern, modular architecture, removing vendor lock-in and eliminating longongoing scaling issues.
- Our work contributed to Which recognising our site as the #6 electronics site (2019), beating notable competition including Apple and Amazon.
- I brought accounting into the engineering process to introduce cost accountability and reduce idle resource costs by 50%.



### Engineering Lead and Product Owner General Dynamics

2 years Sep 2017 – Sep 2019

I led a research and development group to better understand and solve the Ministry of Defence's problems with app development, integration, and deployment onto distributed military networks. Defence apps are traditionally hard to develop, requiring multi-million-pound investments into physical infrastructure and alignment with many moving dependencies. We helped the UK Army standardise and modernise military app development, opening defence up to wider industry.

- We proved concepts for app integration and testing to reduce release time from 2 years to 3 months.
- We introduced app management and separation technologies to reduce operational downtime by 70%.
- We designed a cloud architecture that securely controls public access to restricted technology.



1 year Sep 2016 – Sep 2017

I worked across multiple engineering teams to create a safety case for an automotive radar and camera fusion vision system.

- We delivered safety cases for driving autonomy level 1 (hands on) applications.
- I trained 40 engineers in Safety Engineering with Model Based Systems Engineering.

# System Architect MBDA Systems

7 years, 3 months June 2009 – Sep 2016

I took overall responsibility for the architecture of a highly disruptive future system that made an ambitious concept vision into reality.

- I created a trade model to identify, assess and resolve the project's major decision points.
- I commissioned research to resolve differences of opinions between critical stakeholders across multiple countries.

I led the flight path management domain for an urgent novel loitering munition. This system demanded fast-paced development in a constantly changing field.

- I worked to understand the users' and stakeholders' core needs to strip the project of unnecessary requirements, bringing us back onto delivery schedule.
- I coordinated development efforts between multiple internal and external software teams.

#### THALES

# Software Engineer Thales

1 year, 9 months Sep 2007 – June 2009

I worked in a small team to quickly deliver novel concepts, including prototypes for novel radar and tracking systems.

- We achieved NATO security accreditation for a Windows Server local network system.
- I provided 8 weeks of customer trials support in Germany.

For more information, please see my portfolio website.

#### Interests

I am a keen martial artist and hold a license to teach Taekwondo for the United Kingdom Taekwondo Association.

In my personal time I like to refresh my developer skills with personal projects, such as:

- Creating small cloud native websites such as this one to host my CV.
- Raspberry Pi projects, such as home automation systems and Pi Holes.
- Creating Selenium scripts to automate repetitive admin tasks.